 	
Education
Indian Institute of Technology Kharagpur                                                                                                             2012 - 2017
Integrated M.Sc(5YR) : Mathematics and Computing                                   

Professional Experience
Simplia, California (Remote)                                                                                                               March 2024 - Aug 2024
Role: Customer Success - Senior Partner
Tech Role
• Developed an AI virtual assistant, seamlessly integrating into client websites to streamline appointment scheduling for end-users.
• Leveraged machine learning algorithms (scikit-learn, TensorFlow) to predict customer behaviour, enhance retention rates, and automate personalized AI-driven growth strategies.
• Utilized data visualization tools (Matplotlib, Seaborn) to deliver actionable insights to stakeholders, improving decision-making processes.
• Collaborated across departments utilizing Google Analytics, SQL, and Tableau to optimize performance tracking, resulting in a 20% increase in client digital marketing ROI.
Managerial Role
• Led a cross-functional Customer Success team of 40+ members, including SEO analysts, web designers, paid ad specialists, social media marketers, and content creators, serving 400+ active small US-based businesses.
• Deployed AI tool (invideo.ai) to automate the creation of short reels for clients' Meta pages, enhancing their social media presence.
• Expanded customer base from 300 to 400+ in just 2 months through marketing initiatives, hackathon events and incentives disbursement.

Credit Suisse Business Analytics, Mumbai                                                                                       July 2017 - March 2019
Role: Model Risk Management Analyst (CCAR) - Model Validation
Job Description: Credit Suisse uses numerous mathematically intensive models to comply with their Risk Reporting requirements. I validated the end to end process for many CCAR models, judging the model's fitness for purpose, commenting on its statistical stability and economic sensibility, replicating its strategic implementation, stress testing, benchmarking, raising action findings, and restricting their use.

• Automation of OLS Regression Model Validation: Automated validation for OLS regression models by implementing statistical tests for heteroscedasticity, autocorrelation, multicollinearity, and normality of residuals, thereby covering 60+ OLS based models.
• Sovereign Probability of Default Model: Independently validated z-scores and identified a Severity 1 issue, leading to reassessment and enhanced risk management strategies.
• Validation of Key Models: Applied rigorous statistical analysis to validate Loss Given Default and Challenger Scenario Expansion models, ensuring compliance with regulatory standards.
• Mentorship: Trained new analysts in R programming and advanced statistical methods. Mentored a junior analyst, leading to their successful transition to a full-time role.

UPSC Experience                                                                                                                          April 2019 - Feb 2024
• UPSC Civil Services Examination: Reached the interview stage, ranking among the top 350 candidates out of over 500,000 applicants, and ranked among the top scorers in Mathematics optional during UPCS Mains 2021.
• SBI PO and RBI Grade B: Successfully cleared preliminary exams, showcasing robust logical and quantitative reasoning skills.

Internship Experience & Projects
Fractal Analytics, Mumbai                                                                                                                                                    2016
• Authored an automation to address missing values treatment, outlier analysis, dimension reduction and clustering aspects.
• Developed an R programming code for facilitating the same using 8 clustering algorithms by testing on various mixed datasets.
• Reduced effective time by 5 man-hours of work per day for the firm, by implementing the user designed interface on portal of CAE.

Practo Technologies Pvt Ltd, Bengaluru                                                                                                                             2015
• Engineered interactive SQL visualizations for the Fit dashboard; these insights informed strategic decisions that drove a 25%  improvement in user retention rates by highlighting key growth trends in product features.
Master's Thesis Project
• Incorporating a hybrid of collaborative filtering and content based recommender systems to suggest movies to active users of a website.

Technical skills
• Languages, Tools and Softwares: Python, R, SQL, C/C++, Git/Github, Tableau, Power BI, HTML, CSS, Microsoft Office
• Machine Learning: Sci-kit, Pandas, Matplotlib, NumPy, TensorFlow, Google Analytics
• Coursework: Data Structure and Algorithms, Prompt Engineering, Database Management System.

Extracurricular Activities and Interests
• Budgeted, Audited and Managed expenditures worth INR 12 million for the techno-management fest Kshitij of college as Finance Head.
• Achieved a personal highest rating of 1750 on chess.com and also a member of the inter-hall chess team at college.
• Took part in charity competitions during International Women's Day, Year end annual dance performance, and CSR Activities while working at Credit Suisse.
